有人吗
Hello.
有人在吗
Is anybody here?
有人吗
Hello.
我按你的要求来了
I came like you asked.
有人吗
Hello.
为了庆祝我们终于欢聚一堂
In celebration of our finally getting together
共进晚餐
for dinner,
我做了
I have made...
非常特别的甜点
a very special dessert.
玛莎  看起来就非常好吃
Martha, that looks incredible.
好吃到死  真的
It's to die for, literally.
我管这道甜点叫"致命巧克力"
I call it "Death by chocolate."
鉴于您的下厨经历
Now given your baking experience,
这算是预言吗
Is that a prediction?
看来厨艺不在你的天赋范围内啊  玛莎
I take it cooking's not one of your talents, Martha.
不算是
Well, not really.
我将自己的创造力保留在了
I sort of save my creative energy
更有价值完美呈现的技艺上  "演技"
to perfect a more worthy craft...acting.
你呢  吉姆
And what about you, Jim?
工作还顺利吗
How's the law treating you?
还行  最近有个集体诉讼的案子
Uh, good. I've got a class action lawsuit.
我挺忙的
That's, uh, keeping me pretty busy.
不错
Nice.
我希望你有时间放松下  吉姆
Oh, well, I hope you find time to cut loose, Jim,
做些有趣的事
And just do something fun.
当然了
Oh, of course.
我在尝试偶尔参加
I-I try to take in a baseball game
棒球比赛
every now and again.
老天
Ooh, lord.
棒球
Baseball.
那不是闷到死的运动吗
Isn't that dreadfully dull?
这项运动要求
Well, it requires
有一定的耐性
a certain patience.
就是相当地没激情吧
A certain lack of pulse, you mean.
我想
I think, uh,
我爸喜欢的是这项运动的精妙之处
what my dad responds to is the game's nuance.
是的  当然了  这项运动也有优点
Oh, well, yes, of course. It has its merits.
我想我母亲的意思是
Yeah, I think my mother just means
这项运动不是
it's not exactly, uh,
令人激动型的
action-packed.
对  但这取决于
Right, but that would
你如何看待它  对吧
depend on how you look at it, right?
对  在我看来这项运动是
Yeah, I mean I suppose it does appeal
更加...  正经的活动
to the more... serious,
更加
More...
有眼光的群体
Discerning crowd.
吉姆
Jim...
你这句话到底是什么意思
What exactly does that mean?
只是说演员  天性使然
Just that actors, by their nature,
不算世界上最一本正经的人  对吧
aren't the most serious people in the world, right?
是这样吗
Oh, is that so?
所以你觉得我这个人不正经么
So you think I'm not a serious person?
我们开吃甜点怎么样
How about if we dive in to this dessert?
说实话  那个"致命"的话题
Because honestly, that whole death thing...
比现在的话题轻松多了
is sounding pretty good right now.
市中心有谋杀案
There's been a murder downtown.
够近的
Close enough.
真抱歉我们得走了
I'm so sorry that we have to run.
你们两个要小心哦
You two be careful.
你们两个也是
Yeah, you guys, too.
我只是说  还有更糟糕的晚宴
I'm just saying, there have been worse dinners.
比如呢
Like what?
我想到了《异形》里的晚宴场景
Well, the dining scene from "Alien" comes to mind.
说实话  要是异形从我爸的胸口里钻出来
Honestly, a creature bursting out of my dad's chest
说不定还能搞活下气氛
might have lightened the mood.
其实我们该料到这局面的
I guess we should've expected it.
他们两人的背景完全不同
They come from such different worlds.
你母亲应该学会照顾下他人的感受
Yeah, well, your mom should've been more sensitive to that.
等等  什么
Wait. What?
谢谢
Thanks.
打扮得这么漂亮啊
Ooh. You look nice.
还擦了口红  约会之夜吗
Lipstick, huh? Date night?
不是  和她爸我妈一起吃晚饭
No, dinner with her dad and my mom.
这么快  怎么样
Wow. Already? How'd that go?
好吧  说到父亲[神父]
Okay. Well, speaking of fathers,
这里就有一位
we have one right over here.
乔·麦克默瑞神父  52岁
Father Joe Mcmurtry, 52.
房产经纪人带人来看这里
Real estate lady showed up to show the property...
结果却找到了"宗教"
And found religion instead.
那么  知道
So... Do we know
被害人来这个废弃建筑做什么吗
what our victim was doing in an abandoned building?
还不知道
Not yet.
而且他家离这里很远  他的教区在住宅区
And he's a long way from home. His parish is uptown.
死亡时间
Time of death?
昨晚7点至10点间
Between 7:00 and 10:00 last night.
死因看起来是胸部中了三枪
Likely cause of death, three to the chest.
伤口集中  凶手是个神枪手
That's a tight grouping. Killer's a marksman.
也很谨慎  他捡走了所有的弹壳
Careful, too. He picked up all the spent shell casings.
有摄像头吗
Security cams?
没有拍到这栋建筑的
None of 'em are pointing at this building.
感觉像内行人做的
Well, this looks like the work of a pro.
有人暗杀了神父
Someone had a priest assassinated?
感觉像教廷阴谋
It's like a vatican conspiracy.
对  《达芬奇密码》
Ah, it's "The Davinci Code."
也可能不是
Or not.
不如我们调查下麦克默瑞的情况
So why don't we look into Mcmurtry's life
看看有没有人有谋杀动机吧
and see if anyone had motive?
一位修女会正在中心区见我们  她是他的同事
A nun is meeting us downtown. She worked closely with him.
可能会提供有用的线索
So she might be able to shed some light.
多谢  知道了
Thanks. Yeah. We got it.
那个
So, uh...
警员在排查中调查到了恰姆森酒馆
Units on the canvass got a hit on Chumson's Tavern.
那里的酒保
Bartender there--
杰瑞·詹金斯  说他知道这起谋杀
Jerry Jenkins-- says he knows about the murder
但他只肯跟探长说
but he'll only speak to a detective.
好  卡塞尔和我去找他谈话
Okay, Castle and I will talk to him.
你们去和修女谈
You guys chat with the nun.
等等
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait a second.
我们要询问修女
We're interviewing a nun?
对  我唱白脸
Yeah, and I'm gonna be the good cop.
你唱红脸  所以
You're gonna be the bad cop, so...
考虑到我的顾客容易被穿警服的警官吓跑
I asked for a detective seeing as how my customers
所以我就要求了和能穿便服的警探见面
tend to get scared away by uniformed cops.
杰瑞  对于这起谋杀案你都知道什么
Jerry, what do you know about the murder?
昨晚这个家伙晃了进来  里奥
Last night this guy wanders in--Leo.
说他听见了第五街拐角处的枪声
says he heard shots on the corner of 5th,
接着他就看见有人从街上的楼里跑出来
then he seen some guy hustling out of the building there.
于是今天
Then today,
我就听说有牧师被杀了
I hear some priest got popped.
这么说里奥是目击证人
So this Leo was a witness.
知道他现在在哪里吗
Any idea where leo is now?
他喝多了
He got pretty lit,
我就送他上了出租车
So I loaded him in a cab and sent him home
回他在布朗克斯区的家
up in the Bronx.
还记得地址吗
Do you remember the address?
当然
Sure.
223街  9245号
9245 223rd street.
-这边走  -好的
- Right this way. - Oh, okay.
一个修女步入了警局
A nun walks into a precinct...
就像个糟糕笑话的开头
It's like the beginnings of a bad joke.
想借把梳子什么的吗
Want to borrow a comb or something?
闭嘴
Shut up.
你知道这让我想起什么了
You know what this reminds me of?
以前看过一部交换身体的电影
Watching one of those body-switching movies,
里面的哥们儿看起来是个成人
where the guy looks like a grown man,
但其实他就12岁
but he's actually 12.
我告诉你
Hey, let me tell you something--
天主教学校就是个战场
Catholic school is like combat.
除非你去过  否则你根本就不知道
Unless you've been there, you don't know.
我去过  战场
Uh, I have been there-- in combat--
那可比什么老女人糟糕多了
And it's way worse than some old lady.
这是黑暗的一天
This is a dark day.
麦克默瑞神父如此富有同情心
Father Mcmurtry was such a caring man,
全身心的奉献于教区居民和社区
so devoted to his parishioners, his community.
他不该有此命运
That he shouldn't meet such a fate...
玛丽修女  我们想就麦克默瑞神父
Sister Mary, we have a few questions for you
问你一些问题
about father mcmurtry.
当然  除非你准备好了  玛丽修女
That is, if you're up for it, Sister Mary.
我可以告诉你关于神父的任何事情
I can tell you anything you need to know about the father,
包括杀害他的凶手
including who murdered him.
你知道谁杀了他
You know who killed him?
我刚才不是说过了吗
Isn't that what I just said?
我一直担心
I was afraid
他们的友谊会惨淡收场
their friendship would end badly.
但是神父却总是去信任别人
But the father was so trusting,
总是试图拯救迷失的灵魂
always trying to save lost souls,
即使灵魂已经像这个男人一样黑暗了
even souls as black as that man's.
什么男人  玛丽修女
What man, Sister Mary?
迈克尔·多兰
Michael Dolan.
就是那个迈基·多兰
This is mickey dolan-- the mobster,
那个效力于奥莱利家族的黑手党
the enforcer for the O'Reilly family?
正是他
The very same.
他和多兰一起长大
He and Dolan grew up together.
我曾试着提醒他
I-I tried to warn him,
但是他总是相信
but he always believed
自己可以帮助多兰先生走上正路
he could set Mr. Dolan on a better path.
他死的时候还深信不疑
He died believing it.
如果他们是朋友
If they were friends,
你为什么会觉得多兰先生杀了他
why do you think that Dolan killed him?
两天前  他们在
They had a terrible fight
教堂外大吵了一架
outside the church two days ago.
虽然我不知道原因为何
I don't know what it was about,
但是神父之后一直很不安
but the father was very upset afterwards.
非常不安
Very upset.
但是  一次吵架并不能证明
Well, a fight alone doesn't prove--
我还没说完
I wasn't finished.
当然  对不起
Of course. I'm--I'm sorry.
正如我刚说的
As I was about to say,
昨晚六点
last night at 6:00,
神父接了个电话  弥撒还没结束就走了
the father got a call and left in the middle of mass.
他告诉我电话是有关多兰的
He told me the call was about Dolan.
神父和黑手党
ah, the priest and the mobster.
这可是经典故事情节啊
It's a classic story.
儿时的朋友  一个响应了崇高的召唤
Friends since childhood. One takes a higher calling
而另一个却走上了犯罪和谋杀之路
while the other follows a path to crime and murder.
如果这个目击证人可以指认出多兰
Well, if this witness can I.D. Dolan,
那他的道路就直通州立监狱了
then his path is gonna lead straight to state prison.
我还是觉得我们应该坐地铁
I still think we should've taken the subway.
在这里停车有点危险
It's kind of dangerous to park up here.
没事的
It's gonna be fine.
你之前说  我妈应该照顾他人感受
What exactly did you mean earlier
到底是什么意思
when you said my mother could be more considerate?
我只是  我的意思是
I just--I meant that
我希望你能让她别再
I wished that you would've asked her
批评我爸了
to stop criticizing my dad.
她只是在发表观点而已
She was just expressing an opinion
表达方式其实和你爸
in much the same way your father was
说我妈又轻浮又傻一样
when he basically called my mom flighty and stupid.
我爸从没那么说过  卡塞尔
My dad never said that, Castle.
你猜怎么着  还是别说了
You know what? Just drop it.
好吧
Fine.
公平起见  你知道
You know, to be fair,
她只是对他的娱乐消遣发表了观点
She was just commenting about his pastime,
而他却在侮辱她
while he was insulting her.
卡塞尔  小心
Castle, watch it.
怎么了  这里区别大了
What? There's a big difference--
别动
Don't.
扔掉它
Drop it.
扔掉你的手机和钱包
Toss your phones and wallet.
好吧
All right.
你们这可是在犯大错
You guys are making a big mistake.
我是个警察
I'm a cop.
他们一定在查里奥的事
They must be after Leo.
我们该给老大打个电话
We should call the boss.
你们口中的老大是指迈基·多兰吗
Oh, the--the boss as in Mickey Dolan?
我们已经知道麦克默瑞的事了
We know about McMurtry.
在你们还没铸成大错之前  快走吧
Just walk away while you got a chance.
你是见不到目击证人的
You're not getting that witness.
外面吵什么呢
Hey, what's all the noise out here?
抱歉  非常抱歉
Sorry! Sorry. I'm sorry.
等等  你们是谁
Wait. Who are you?
-纽约警局  -快开门
- NYPD. - Open up!
-马上开门  -这些锁顶不了多久
- Open up now! - These locks won't hold.
开门
Open up!
卡塞尔  把那个挪过来  我们得把门堵上
Castle, bring that over. We gotta block the door.
-帮把手行吗  -当然
- Little help? - Yeah.
-电话不通  -他们一定已经把线路掐断了
- It's dead. - They must have cut the line.
这是怎么回事  发生什么事了
What is this? What the hell is going on?
我们是来救你的
We're here to save you.
把人交给我们  你们不会有事的
Just give us the guy and we won't hurt you!
我感觉他是骗人的
Somehow I don't believe him.
什么人  是指我吗
What guy? Am I the guy?
对  就是你
Yeah, you're the guy.
开门
Open up!
他们找我干什么
What do they want with me?
你看见的那个拿枪的男人
That guy you saw holding a gun?
他杀人了  你现在是目击证人
Well, he killed somebody, and you're the witness.
一个他们想灭口的目击证人
A witness they want to get rid of.
这下糟了  糟了
Okay, this is not good. Not good.
他们怎么知道我看到了什么
H-how do they even know what I saw?
跟我们的消息来源一样  你在酒吧没把嘴管好
The same way we do. You ran your mouth off at a bar.
但是  那时很黑
But it was--it was dark.
我根本看不清太多东西
I mean, I didn't even really see that much.
在他们看来  你看到的已经够了
As far as they're concerned, you saw enough.
老天爷  我们得从这出去
Oh, god. We-- we gotta get outta here.
还用你说
Do you think?
快点  伙计们  多兰的手下
Come on, guys. It's not going to
要不了多久就会撞破那道门的
take Dolan's boys long to get through that door.
你们最好赶快开门
You better open up!
什么  多兰  迈基·多兰  那个黑帮老大吗
I'm sorry. Dolan? As in Mickey Dolan, the--the mobster?
老天  我们最后会落得浮尸河中
Oh, god. We're gonna end up floating in the river
死无葬身之地的
with cement shoes on.
准确的说  如果你穿着胶粘鞋
Yes, well, technically, if you have cement shoes,
-你是浮不起来的  -什么
- you're not gonna be floating. - What?
-什么  -你说得对  我真是在瞎闹
- What? - You're right. That's not helping.
快走吧
Let's go.
妹子  你的车哪去了
Dude, where's your car?
-我的车呢  -你的车呢
- Where's my car? - Where's your car?
刚刚就停在这
It was right here.
你把车停在这  你开玩笑吧
You parked here? Are you kidding me?
你看不见周围是什么情况吗
Don't you see this neighborhood?
一句都别说
Don't.
快跑  快跑  快跑
Go. Go, go, go, go, go!
去开车
Get the car.
看来那个修女没说错
So the nun was right.
麦克默瑞神父的确跟迈基·多兰有过冲突
Father McMurtry did fight with Mickey Dolan.
教堂外头的监控录像
Surveillance cam footage outside the church
证实了玛丽修女说的话
backs Sister Mary's story.
我一直坚信修女是绝不会撒谎的
Not that I'd ever doubt a nun.
麦克默瑞接到的那通电话查得怎么样了
What about the phone call McMurtry got?
是多兰打的吗
You trace it to Dolan?
是从公用电话打的
Yeah, it was made from a pay phone.
那家伙已经在
The guy spent 20 years
爱尔兰黑帮里混了二十年
rising through the ranks of the Irish mob.
会掩盖自己的踪迹不足为奇
Not surprising he'd cover his tracks.
多兰和他的夺命小分队
Dolan and his kill squad
不仅残忍而且狡猾聪明
are as smart as they are ruthless.
作为奥莱利家族的执行者
And as the enforcer for the O'Reilly family,
他是多起凶案的嫌疑犯
he's the prime suspect in dozens of hits.
只是我们一直没能抓住他的把柄
Only we've never been able to make a case against him.
分队刚从多兰家回来
Unis came back from Dolan's apartment.
看起来他已经好一段时间没回去过了
Looks like he hasn't been there in a while.
集团犯罪专案组知道他在哪吗
Does the Organized Crime Task Force know where he is?
他们说  他已经消失好几天了
They say that he's been off their radar the past few days.
说可能是因为帮派出大事了
Word is, there's something big going on--
有可能是抢地盘
Maybe a turf war
也有可能是奥莱利家庭内部的权力纷争
or a power struggle within the O'Reilly family.
可能会出人命
There may be bloodshed,
所以他们认为多兰可能藏起来了
so they figure that Dolan went underground.
那男人杀害了一名神父  我们不能让他就这么逃了
The guy took out a priest. We can't just let him disappear.
即使我们知道他人在哪
No, no, even if we knew where he was,
手上的证据也不足以起诉他
we don't have enough to charge him.
把多兰的头像发给贝克特
Shoot Beckett Dolan's mug shot.
看看他们的目击证人能不能认出他
See if their witness can I.D. Him.
这就去
Yeah, we're on it.
是他们吗
Is it them?
是的  就是他们
Yeah, that's them.
今天晚上现在正式被搞砸了
Well, our night has officially been trashed.
快点  卡塞尔  公用电话  在他们回来之前
Hurry, Castle. The pay phone, before they get back.
真不敢相信这东西还存在
I can't believe they still have these things.
好嘞  有没有人有
All right, does anybody have a--
要一美金  你开玩笑吧
A dollar? Are you kidding me?
打911不用钱
You don't need coins to call 9-1...
我们得快离开这
We gotta keep moving.
太棒了  真是太棒了
Oh, great. That's just great.
我们被困在这郊区地带
We're stuck in the outer borough
后面有两个黑帮在追杀
with two mobsters trying to kill us
现在还失去了和外界联系的方式
and no means of contacting the outside world.
里奥  你别太紧张了  行吗
Leo, would you just relax, okay?
我们只需要找到一台电话
We just gotta find a phone.
附近有全天营业的店铺吗
Are there any 24-hour businesses around here?
我没见过
No, not that I know of.
也许我们可以找别人借一下手机
Maybe we could borrow a cell from someone.
说得轻巧  找谁啊
Yeah, from who?
这一带  这个时候根本不会有人出门
Around here, no one's out this time of night
-除非他们是活腻了  -里奥
- unless they have a death wish. - Leo--
老天爷呀  这太疯狂了
Oh, my god. This is-- this is insane.
这种事不该发生在我身上的
This kind of stuff doesn't happen to me.
我只是个报商  我是卖报纸的
I'm a paper salesman. I sell paper.
里奥  能专心点吗
Leo, can you focus?
好
Yes.
你会没事的  大家都不会有事
You're gonna be okay. We're all gonna be okay.
我们只需要通知局里的人
We just have to contact my precinct.
好啊  怎么联系
Yeah. How?
我想我知道
I think I know.
警监
Captain.
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
是吗  说来听听
Okay. What's your problem?
我们想发多兰的头像
We tried to send Dolan's mug shot,
可是联系不上贝克特或卡塞尔
but we can't reach Beckett or Castle.
我们打过他们的手机
We called their phones,
呼叫过贝克特的无线电
Beckett's radio,
连卡塞尔的妈妈都联系过了
even called Castle's mom.
你查过她的警车在哪儿吗
Did you ping her cruiser?
查了  全球定位系统查到
Yeah, GPS shows it's
车往泽西的收费站开去了
heading down the Jersey turnpike.
莱恩  让骑警拦下那辆车
Ryan, have troopers intercept that car.
对了  埃斯波西托
Oh, and, Esposito,
你去被害人住处
Go to that witness' address,
看看到底是怎么回事
find out what the hell's going on.
这就去
Right on.
卡塞尔  没用的
Castle, it's not working.
会有用的  我是在扰人清梦
It will. I'm disturbing the peace.
一旦忍无可忍了就只能
They'll have no choice but to--
送我瓶啤酒
offer me a beer.
下次我就不会砸偏了
Next time I won't miss.
你们知道现在几点吗
You have any idea what time it is?
是的  劳驾  我们需要帮忙
Yes. Please, we need your help.
没错  还敢接着按的话
Yeah, you gon' need some help all right
你们就真需要找人帮忙了
if you don't stop buzzing.
在我动手之前趁早把手拿开
So knock it off before I do something.
是吗  你打算如何
Yeah, what are you gonna do,
报警
Call a cop?
那你就尽管报啊
Matter of fact, go ahead.
你不报警我就要按
I'm not gonna stop buzzing till you do.
报警  警察才不来这地方  哥们
Cops? Cops don't come up here, Jack.
这片地头  我们靠自己
This hood, we're on our own.
你再按
You keep that up,
我就下来打得你满地找牙
I'm-a come down there and hurt you real bad.
这就是你的计划么
So that's your big plan,
招惹更多的人来灭我们么
make more people want to kill us?
不是
No.
走吧
Let's go.
对了  赶紧走
Yeah, keep on walking.
也许打一架能招来警察
Maybe a fight will bring the cops.
是啊  没错
Sure. Yeah.
没准把追杀我们的人也招来了
Or maybe the guys that are chasing us?
先假设我们还有命活着吧
Assuming we survive.
我是想帮大家脱离险境
Hey, I'm trying to get us out of this.
卡塞尔  就是你让我们
Castle, you're the reason that we are
现在走投无路的
in this in the first place.
什么
What?
下次要有两个杀手想对我们不利的时候
The next time two thugs are about to jump us
如果我说"小心"  求你乖乖听话行吗
and I say, "Watch it," Why don't you just listen?
我说不该开车来你怎么不听呢
Maybe if you had listened to me about the car--
行了  我觉得气氛有点紧张了
Okay. Wow. I'm picking up some tension here,
不过我觉得
and I'm sensing it has
和两个疯子追杀我们没多大关系
less to do with the two maniacs chasing us
只是你俩的内部矛盾
and more to do with the two of you.
既然我的命已经交给了你们
And seeing as my life is in your hand...
告诉你  我俩很好
You know what? We're fine.
有人就不妙了  你干嘛啊
Some of us more than others. What are you doing?
车里有部手机
There's a cell phone in the car.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
不过手机设了密码
And it's password protected.
好样的  报警声把他们引过来了
Nice work. The alarm brought those guys back.
莱恩
Ryan.
兄弟
Bro...
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
他们应该没看见我们
Okay. I don't think they saw us.
他们不会罢休的
Yeah, they're not gonna stop looking.
也许我该试着跟他们谈谈
Maybe I should try and talk to them.
不然怎么办  就待在这儿
Well, so I should what, just--just stay here
等着被他们发现吗
and wait for them to find us?
也许天无绝人之路
Well, maybe that's not the only option.
只要我能试出这部手机的密码
If I can figure out the passcode for this phone,
我们就能打电话了
we can use it.
你现在成了有龙纹身的男孩了么
So you're the boy with the dragon tattoo now?
组合可能不下一万
There's, like, 10,000 possibilities.
你还有更好的对策吗
Do you have a better idea?
这里最近的地铁在哪儿
Where's the nearest subway?
现在她想起来找地铁了
Now she wants to take the subway.
C线离这里六个街区开外
The "C" Train's 6 blocks from here.
好  每个周日的午夜以后
Okay, so on weeknights after midnight,
它每隔半小时都会准时发一次车
it runs every half-hour on the hour.
现在几点了
What time is it now?
1:20
1:20.
1:20  好吧  1点半那趟我们赶不上
1:20. Okay. So we're not gonna make the 1:30.
但是能赶上2点整那趟
But we can make the 2:00.
我们就好好等个十分钟
We just sit tight for ten minutes,
然后拼命跑过去
and then we'll make a run for it.
地铁又不是美国铁路公司  没有时刻表
The subway is not Amtrak. There is no schedule.
有的
Yes, there is.
我从小就住在这儿  没有时刻表
I've lived here all my life. There's no schedule.
我也从小住在这儿
I've lived here all my life as well,
的确是有  只是你不知道
and there is, you just don't know about it
因为它并不总是准点
Because it doesn't always run on time.
所以才说没有时刻表
Which is the same thing as not having a schedule.
所以怎样  我们去了  地铁误了点
So what happens-- we go there, the train is late,
接着呢  我们就等死了
and then what, we're sitting ducks?
我们已经在等死了
We're sitting ducks now.
好吧  我开始觉得
Okay, I'm starting to feel
我还是在外面待着安全点了
like I might be safer outside.
好吧
Okay, fine.
如果我试不出密码
Look, if I can't figure out the code,
我们就试着往地铁逃
then we make a break for the subway.
行
Fine.
我真是想不死都难了
I am so gonna die.
有个房客看见两个人闯进了门
A tenant saw two guys break down the door
然后冲进房间
and push into the apartment.
听上去像是多兰派人来抓证人
Sounds like Dolan sent guys to get the witness,
而卡塞尔和贝克特也一起被抓了
and Castle and Beckett got caught in the middle.
贝克特的车怎样  你找到了吗
What about Beckett's car, did you find it?
巡警在高速上拦下了贝克特的警车
A trooper stopped Beckett's cruiser on the turnpike.
像是些不法分子抢了车开着玩
Seems a couple of delinquents took it for a joyride.
很有可能是多兰的人劫走了他们
Well, it's likely Dolan's people took them...
或更糟
or worse.
我找到了负责这楼的巡警
Well, I got unis canvassing this building,
看看有没有人知道些情况
see if anybody knows anything.
好  跟他们配合  然后赶回来
Okay, coordinate with 'em and then you get back here
越快越好
A.S.A.P.
盖茨警监
Captain Gates?
Captain Gates.
你们二位来这里干什么
What are you two doing down here?
我接到埃斯波西托的电话后
Well, after I got a call from detective Esposito,
非常担心  所以我联系...
I became very concerned, so I checked in with--
我联系不上凯特  什么情况
I can't reach Katie. What's the situation?
没什么大不了的
There's no cause for alarm.
只不过我们暂时无法
It's just that we're having trouble
定位他们的确切位置
pinpointing their precise location.
省省吧  你这演员烂透了
Oh, please stop. You are a terrible actress.
他们要不是真的担心
There is no way that anyone would've called me
他们是绝不会联系我的
if they weren't really worried,
而我就想知道到底是怎么回事
and I want to know what is going on here.
好吧
Okay.
他们去面见一个证人
They went to interview a witness,
我们失去了联系
and we lost contact.
但我们正在尽最大努力找寻他们
But we're doing our best to find them.
因此  我建议你们都回家去
So I suggest you both go home
一有消息我就通知你们
and I'll call you the second I know more.
不知道我们的孩子发生了什么
I am not leaving until I know
我哪里都不去
what has happened to our children.
我也是
Neither am I.
行了  理查德给分局
All right, where is that...
买的那个豪华咖啡机放哪儿了
fancy coffee machine that Richard bought for the precinct,
那里吗
over there?
在休息室
The break room.
好  你也要...
Okay. You want, uh...
我可不想去告诉那两位
I don't want to have to tell those two
我把他们的孩子弄丢了
that I lost their kids.
快告诉我查到多兰的线索了
Tell me you have something on Dolan.
没查到
No, nothing on Dolan,
但我查了他的同伙
but I started looking into his associates.
前几个星期  他们都分散在各地
During the past week, they've all split town.
很可能跟这次的地盘战有关
It could have something to do with this turf war,
但我能定位到多兰
but I was able to locate
其中一个还在附近的小弟  科林·克拉克
one of Dolan's guys who's still around--Colin Clark.
可他明天一早就要飞都柏林了
But he's flying to Dublin tomorrow morning.
带他来
Then bring him in.
好的
All right.
你看到什么了吗
You see anything?
没
No.
但这不表示他们没在外面
But it doesn't mean that they're not out there.
我搞定了
I got it.
搞定了  怎么弄的
You got it. How?
我做的就是想手机主人之所想
All I had to do is get inside the mind of the owner of the phone.
她开的是迷你宝马吧
She drives a mini, right?
试一下  不对
Tried that. Nada.
看机壳的背面  爱心  试试"爱"
Look at the back of the case. Hearts. Tried "Love."
还是不对
Still no.
但你看这锁屏画面
But look at the lock screen.
怎么了
What?
密码就是这猫的名字
The password's the cat's name.
-没错  -太好了  那猫叫什么
- Exactly. - Great. So what's the cat's name?
他不知道
He doesn't know.
我是不知道  但一等我们想出来
I don't know, but as soon as we figure it out...
我们就成了
we're golden.
卡塞尔  我们要找的是真正的线索
Castle, we're looking for some real solutions.
我正在找啊
And I'm offering them.
怎么会  就盯着一个永远都解不开锁的手机吗
How, by focusing on a phone that's never gonna--
你说呢
You were saying?
接电话可不需要密码哦
And I don't need the passcode to answer.
你好啊  天使  感谢你的来电
Hello, you godsend. Thank god you called.
不管你是谁  你最好把手机还给我
Hey, whoever you are, you better bring my phone back.
等等  这是你的手机
Wait. This is your phone?
对  我需要这个手机
Yeah, I need that phone.
里面有我家罗拉所有的照片
It's got all my pictures of Lola on it,
我所有的应用程序和所有的歌
all my apps, all my music. Hey, hey, hey,
叫她打911  告诉她我们在哪儿
Tell her to call 9-1-1 and tell her where we are.
行行行  听着  我们在利马特公园
Okay, okay. Listen, listen, we're in Leimart park.
对对对  我知道你在哪里
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I know exactly where you are.
我用GPS跟踪了你
I used GPS to track you.
是...是吗  好  很好
You d--you did? Okay, good. Good.
那打911吧  我们有麻烦了
Then, uh, then call 9-1-1. We are in trouble.
是吗  你是有麻烦了
Oh, yeah? Well, damn right, you are,
等我抓到你  你麻烦大了
especially if I get my hands on you.
告诉她杀手的事
Tell her about the killer.
什么
What?
杀了她  你还威胁我吗
Kill her? Are you threatening me?
不不不  不是杀了她  是杀手  杀手
N-no, no. Not kill her. Killer. Killer.
我们被追杀了  你得报警
We're being chased. We need you to call 9-1--
喂  喂  喂
Hel-hel-hello?
你干嘛由着她挂电话  我们就快成功了
Why'd you let her hang up? We were so close.
对  我是由着她挂了
Yes, I let her hang up.
听着  还没结束呢
Look, all is not lost.
她告诉我密码了
She told me the passcode.
那只猫叫罗拉
The cat's name is Lola.
对咯  现在谁是天才呀
Bingo. Who's the genius now?
我要做的仅仅是...
Now all I need to do is--
不  不不不不
No. No, no, no.
怎么了怎么了怎么了
What, what, what, what?
她远程关闭了手机
She remotely disabled the phone.
大伙儿  外面有辆出租车
You guys, there's a cab outside.
开得够慢  我想咱们能追上它
It's going slow enough. I think we can catch it.
我的脚踝  脚踝
My ankle. My ankle.
快去  拦下那辆出租车  拦下它
Go. Go stop the cab. Stop the cab.
里奥这有我呢  我来
I got Leo. I got Leo.
不是吧  老兄  真是被你打败了
Seriously, man? You are killing me.
干嘛  干嘛  下班儿啦
Hey, hey, hey. "Off duty."
不  求求你  有紧急情况
No, please. This is an emergency.
我是警察
I'm a police officer.
我还是暹罗的苏丹王呢
I'm the Sultan of Siam.
这些是我忠心耿耿的臣民
These are my loyal subjects.
不不  你没弄明白  这可不是开玩笑
No, no, you don't understand. This isn't a joke.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
看得出你麻烦缠身
You got trouble written all over you.
你把我们送到市里  我给你1000美金
I will give you $1,000 to get us into the city.
-当真  -是的
- Really? - Yeah.
把钱拿出来瞧瞧
Let's see the money.
我现在身上没有
Well, I don't have it on me
不过我这有块好表
but I do have this lovely watch.
别  别啊  别走
No! No, no, no, no.
可在水下看时间
It tells time underwater.
能显示三个不同时区的时间
It tells time in three different time zones!
现在  它告诉我该拔腿就跑
And right now it's telling me, it's time to go.
-快跑  快跑  -我的天啊  老天啊
- Move! Come on. Move! - Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
走走走  快走
Go. Go, go, go. Go, go.
跟上
Come on.
快点
Come on!
追
Go!
慢着  这走  来
Wait. Here. Come on.
老天
Oh, man.
-嘘  -对不起
- Shh. - I'm sorry.
脚踝伤得挺严重  没法着地
I hurt my ankle pretty badly. I can't stand on it.
别出声  那些家伙
shh. It's not gonna take
很快就会发现我们的藏身之地的
those guys very long to figure out where we went.
是啊  可他站都站不稳
Yeah, but if he can't stand,
行动起来就不方便了
it's gonna be hard to move.
更别说跑了
Yes, even harder to run.
他们一定藏在这附近
They gotta be here somewhere.
科林·克拉克
Colin Clark.
前科一大摞啊
Quite a list of priors.
上面说你涉嫌为奥莱利家
It says here you're a suspected foot soldier
打杂[双关步兵]
for the O'Reilly family.
我还喜欢在沙滩上漫步
I also like long walks on the beach.
你们无权把我拘留问话
Your guys had no right to bring me here.
我可没时间陪你周旋  科林
I don't have time for games, Colin.
迈基·多兰在哪儿
Where is Mickey Dolan
他对贝克特探长
and what did he do
和卡塞尔先生做了什么
with Detective Beckett and Mr. Castle?
你不能把我留在这  你手里没有把柄
You can't keep me here. You got nothin' on me.
我可以扣留你24小时
Oh, I can hold you for 24 hours.
你的航班七个小时后就起飞了
Your plane leaves in seven.
是不是奥莱利家族起内讧了
Are things about to get ugly inside the O'Reilly clan?
所以你才这么急切地想离开
Is that why you're so eager to get out of dodge?
亲爱的  我不会让你误点的
Oh, honey, I'm gonna let you catch your flight.
娘的  我还会亲自送你去机场呢
Hell, I'll even drive you to the airport.
但你得从实招来
But you will tell me what I need to know.
你们这些条子根本不知道要出什么乱子
You cops have no idea what's about to go down,
不知道多兰的诡计是什么
what Dolan's really into.
我不在乎多兰的诡计是什么
I don't care what he's into.
我要将他绳之以法  我的人安然无恙
I want him and I want my people.
你知道我想要什么吗
You know what I want?
我的律师
My lawyer.
他知道
He knows.
他知道他们在哪儿
He knows where they are.
要让我单独跟他谈几分钟
A few minutes alone in there,
我也能套出他的话
I can get him to talk about it, too.
多兰的诡计是什么
What Dolan's really into?
奥莱利家族并没有起内讧
So there's no O'Reilly family feud.
他刚才说的就是这个意思
That's basically what he just said.
那为什么每个人都行事匆匆
So why is everybody scrambling?
这有什么关系
What does that matter?
要是我们知道多兰有何阴谋
Well, if we understand what Dolan was into,
我们也许就能找到他
It might tell us where to find him.
你去哪儿
Where you going?
我想看看技术部门是否
I want to see if tech
能解读他和麦克默瑞神父视频里的唇语
can lip-read that video of him and Father Mcmurtry.
看看他当时说什么了  如何
Let's find out what he was talking about, huh?
他们还守在外面
They're still out there.
看上去他们不知道我们在哪儿
It doesn't look like they know where we are,
可他们最终会发现的
But they'll figure it out eventually.
他们找不到这里的
Well, they are not getting through here,
不过通往楼上商店的门
but the door to the shop upstairs
是从另一面打开的
opens from the other side.
好极了  等他们发现我们在下面后
Oh, great. So when they figure out we're down here,
他们就能径直下来了
they can come through there.
-那时候我们早走了  -怎么走
- We'll be long gone by then. - How? Okay?
我们这地儿离地铁站更远了
I mean, we're even farther from the subway now,
我还扭了脚
and I hurt my ankle.
我来帮你把脚踝绑住
I'll find something to tape it up.
去你的绑带
Screw tape.
你能在这些盒子里再给我找个脚踝吗
Can you find another ankle in these boxes?
不然  我可跑不了八个街区
Otherwise, I'm not making it 8 blocks.
或许我们用不着跑
We might not have to.
这里有家24小时营业的中餐馆菜单
This is a menu from a 24-hour Chinese restaurant
离这两个街区
2 blocks from here.
要是我们能到那儿  应该就有救了
If we can get there, we should be able to get some help,
我们只需要等这些家伙离开
We just gotta wait for this guy to leave.
找到胶带了吗
Did you find some tape?
是的  没错
Yes, I did.
我还找到了
I also found
一箱工具和一个坏了的民用无线电台
a box of tools and a broken C.B. radio.
不过我觉得我能修好它
But I think I can get it to work.
太好了  你是学工科的吗
Great. You have an engineering degree
还是懂一些电子学
or electronics experience?
都不是  不过《百战天龙》的每一集我都看过
No, but I've seen every episode of "MaCgyver".
怎么了
What?
我什么也没说啊
I didn't say anything.
不用说  看表情就知道
No, you didn't have to.
至少我的办法是比较实际的  卡塞尔
Well, at least I'm offering real-world solutions, Castle,
不像你的
Not TV ones.
恕我冒昧  你们俩怎么了
Okay, I'm sorry. What-- what's wrong with you two?
有人在追杀我们啊
There are people outside that want to kill us.
你们到底怎么了
So what's the problem?
没什么啊
There is no problem.
不  一定有
No, there's a problem.
真的没事
It's nothing.
今晚我们和双方的家长一起吃饭  她老爸
We had dinner with the parents, and her dad--
我爸  应该是你老妈的问题吧
My dad? More like your mom.
明白了
Oh. Oh, m--okay.
这么说你们  你们不仅是搭档
So you guys, you're not just partners.
你们还是
You're, uh...
一对
partners.
我明白了  好吧
I get it. Okay.
我做过上千小时的治疗
I've done over a thousand hours of therapy,
我承认是作为病人  但是我也学到一些东西
Granted, as a patient, but I picked up a few things,
我可以这么跟你们说
And I can tell you this much--
这事跟你们的家长没关系  懂吗
this, uh, thing, it's not about your folks, okay?
那只是个借口
That's just an excuse.
你们之间的争吵
This fight...
是因为你们自己
it's about the two of you.
我都能在纽约警察局
I doubt the NYPD would appreciate
休息室的地板上走出一个坑了
the hole I've been pacing in their break room floor.
所以我还是来陪你吧
I thought I'd join you.
给你带了杯咖啡
Oh. Brought you that.
谢谢
Thank you.
很难喝吧
Oh, it's awful.
还行  只是我平时喝咖啡什么也不加
It's fine. I just normally take my coffee black.
你懂的  很简单  很无聊
You know, simple, boring.
-你不会认为我觉得你很  -没关系的
- Oh, no. You don't think I think you're... - No, it's fine.
-无聊  -没关系的  真的
- boring? - It's fine. It's fine.
这次晚餐聚会有些
I--look, that whole dinner party thing was--
有些可笑
just seemed so absurd.
棒球其实
Baseball is--is--
挺好的
It's fine.
是的  挺好的
Is--yes. It's--it's fine.
吉姆
Jim...
我不知道你是怎么做到的
I don't know how you do this.
我本来以为会习惯这一切
You know, I thought I would get used to this...
儿子的新生活
New part of Richard's life--
危机四伏  永远也不知道...
The constant danger and the never knowing--and I--
但我真的认为总有一天
But I really thought there would come a moment,
会有那么一天
just a moment,
我会不再担心
when the worry would stop.
凯特干这行已经十多年了
Katie's been doing this for more than a decade now,
自从她戴上警徽的那一刻起
and I've... I've had this clench in my gut
我的心就一直提在嗓子眼
since the day they handed her the shield.
但她说过  只要你儿子在她身边
She does say, she always feels safest
她就感到十分安全
when your son's watching her back.
他也这么说过她
He says the same thing about her.
无论他们现在在哪
At least wherever they are,
至少他们有彼此可以依靠
they have each other to lean on.
里奥刚才说的太不靠谱了  对吧
What Leo said was crazy, right?
当然了
Yeah. Come on.
我们要是连为什么争吵都不知道
We're a couple of idiots who can't remember
我们真是一对傻冒了
what we were fighting about.
那么
So...
我们到底是为了什么吵架呢
what were we fighting about?
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道的是
I do know that I just--
我只想让这次晚餐进行地顺利
I wanted that dinner to go well,
当它进行地不顺利时
and when it didn't...
你提到了不同的世界
You said "different worlds."
什么
What?
你说他们是两个不同世界的人
You said that they're from different worlds
你说我们应该预料到这一点
and that we should just expect it.
之后我又想起了我们
and then I started thinking about us.
你是世界著名的畅销作家
You're, like, this world-famous, best-selling author,
而我只是个警察
and I'm just this cop and...
我们之间的这段恋情
and we're in this relationship
根本就不应该存在
which makes absolutely no sense on paper.
有时我不禁想问
And sometimes, I just start wondering...
我们是不是在自欺欺人呢
are we just kidding ourselves?
如果我们的美梦破灭怎么办
What if this bubble bursts?
那时我们会怎么样
What are we then?
凯特
Kate...
我们不是我们的家长  明白吗
We're not our parents. All right?
我当时提到两个世界
And--and when I said two different worlds,
并不是说
I didn't mean--
注意
Heads up.
我正在高速公路上  看到了一起惨烈的事故
I'm passing a nasty wreck on the B.Q.E.
喂  喂  能听见我吗
Hello. Hello. Can you hear me?
或许是因为我没有使用无线电语
Maybe I'm not speaking the right language.
总台  总台
Breaker, Breaker,
我发现了一只母熊和两只小熊
I've got a mama bear and two joes
需要搭车把它们送回洞里
who need a ride back to the bear cave.
我曾写过德里克·斯道姆痛扁卡车司机
I once had Derrick Storm beat up a trucker.
-有别人在讲话吗  -只是电磁干扰
- Someone's cutting in. - Ah, it's just static.
喂  能听见吗  能听见我讲话吗
H-hello. Do you copy? Can you copy me?
肯定是话筒坏了
The mic must be broken.
他们走了
Hey, hey. The guy's gone.
现在是跑到那个中餐馆
This is gonna be our best chance
寻求帮助的最好时机
to make a run for the chinese restaurant.
好的  我去
Okay, I'll go.
不行  我们一起去
No. We go together.
他的脚踝能行吗
What, with his ankle?
我们也不能丢下他不管
And--and we can't leave him alone.
单独行动才不会引人注意
And one of us has a better chance of going unnoticed.
卡塞尔  我可是警察
Castle, I'm the cop.
所以你要跟目击证人呆在一起
Which is why you should stay with the witness.
他们想要他的命  而不是我的
Besides, it's him they want dead, not me.
真是多谢提醒
Thanks for the reminder.
听着
Hey.
不用担心我
Don't worry.
我会捎晚饭回来的
I'll bring you back a doggie bag.
好吧  不要引人注意
All right. Just be... Inconspicuous.
我只是个寻常不过的小白
Just an average white guy
在深夜的布朗克斯街道上游荡罢了
walking in the Bronx, middle of the night.
能出什么岔子呢
What could go wrong?
我们明确了
So we think we know
迈基和被害人的争执原因
what Mickey and our victim were fighting about.
摄像头离得太远  没有办法解析唇语
Camera was too far away, so tech couldn't read their lips,
但我们有别的发现
but we found something else.
看迈基离开后发生了什么
Look what happens right after Mickey leaves.
看看车里的人是谁
Check out the guys in the car.
那些人是联邦特工
Those are federal agents.
看上去麦克默瑞对他们泄露了多兰的事
Looks like Mcmurtry was informing on Dolan to the feds.
这就能解释迈基·多兰的杀人动机了
Which explains why Mickey Dolan wanted him dead.
如果联邦的人留意过多兰
And if the feds had eyes on dolan,
他们可能会知道他在哪
they may know where he is.
中餐馆
Chinese restaurant.
美味啊美味
Something smells... Delicious.
你给我老实点
You don't want to do that.
很抱歉我踢了你的...
I'm so sorry about kicking you in the...
你懂得
You know.
没记恨我吧
No hard feelings, right?
没恩怨吧
We're all good?
我是说没...恩怨吧
I mean, we're all... Good?
谁知道呢
I don't know.
那要看你的表现了
That depends on you.
担心吗
Nervous?
不
No.
我只是  想发信号罢了
I'm, uh, I'm just trying to send a message.
我按下按钮时他们可以听到电波干扰
They can hear static when I press the button,
所以我想发求救信号  但是
so I thought I'd send an S.O.S. But...
担心并没有错
It's okay to be worried.
他会没事的
He's gonna be fine.
他足智多谋  所以
He's, he's smart and he's resourceful, so...
声名远扬  来自不同的世界
Larger than life, from another world.
你怎么...
How did you--
拜托  我们在地下室里
Please. We're in a basement.
声音传得很远  我听见你俩的谈话了
Sound carries. I heard.
那可是私人谈话
That was a personal conversation.
你们之间的差距
About how different you two are,
才是你所担心的  不是吗
and that worries you, right?
我现在不想谈这个
I don't want to have this discussion right now.
现在那些差距越来越明显
And those differences that are so charming now,
很可能导致你们关系的破裂
they may end up just pulling you apart.
你以为你是谁  菲尔医生吗[脱口秀主持人]
Who are you, Dr. Phil?
不是的
No.
我只不过是个可能在今晚命丧黄泉
Just a guy that may die tonight
后知后觉生命如此短暂的人罢了
realizing that life's short.
相信我
Trust me.
过好现在的每一秒
Living your life for now
比坐在那里担心未来要有意义得多
makes a lot more sense than worrying about the future.
里奥在哪
So where's Leo?
哪个里奥
Leo who?
你真有趣  不错
You're funny. I like that.
我知道那女的是个警察
So I know the chick's a cop,
但你看上去不像
but you don't smell like NYPD.
你是什么角色
So what's your skin in this game?
我...我是个作家
I'm a--I'm a writer,
跟警局合作
Work with the police department.
是吗  你都写些什么
Oh, yeah? What do you write?
悬疑小说
Mystery novels.
我通常没有耐心看书
Oh. I don't have the patience for books.
但一旦看书  就会直接跳到最后结局
But when I do read, I tend to skip to the last page.
那可浪费了不少乐趣呢  不是吗
Well, that kind of spoils the fun, don't you think?
或许吧
Eh, maybe.
不过我倒是非常擅长构思结局
But I got damn good at figuring out endings.
比如我们之间的小故事
Like in the case of our little story,
我很确信结局只会有一个
I'm pretty sure it's only gonna end one way.
告诉我  那个警察
You're gonna tell me where the hell that cop
把目击证人弄到哪里了
has my witness.
你知道你在说什么吗
You know what you're asking?
我为什么要告诉你
Why would I tell you where they are?
我都马上要死了
I mean, I'm already dead.
干嘛还要把他们也拖下水呢
Why would I let you have them, too?
你会玩扑克吗
You play poker?
我只会兑现我应得的那部分钱
I... I've cashed in my fair share of chips.
我也是
Me, too.
取胜的关键在于能否读懂对手的声势
And I find the key is in reading a man's bluff.
来看看你的技巧如何吧
So let's test your bluffing skills.
我们拦住你的时候
When we picked you up,
你正好想去求救
you were on your way for help.
没错吧  也就是说里奥和那个警察
Right? That means Leo and the cop
正小心翼翼地躲在附近的建筑里
are in a building somewhere, laying low.
是躲在北边
Now is that building on the north side
还是南边呢
or the south side of the street?
北边
North.
那看来是南边
That means south.
我在二二五大道和莱克星敦街交界截住你
We picked you up on the corner of 225th and Lex.
所以他们离这儿只有几个街区
So they're within a couple of blocks.
他们是在227街吗
Are they on 227th?
还是226号街
226th?
或是224街
224th?
看来是224街啊
Ah. 224th it is.
去抓他们
Go get 'em.
他们会转回来的  我们该怎么做
They're coming back. What should we do?
谢谢你能赶过来  卢卡斯探员
Thank you for coming, agent Lucas.
-你之前描述得很紧急  -的确很紧急
- You made it sound urgent. - It is urgent.
我手下一名警探和她的同事失踪了
One of my detectives and her colleague are missing.
不知道我能怎样帮到你
I'm not sure how I can help you.
你可以告诉我迈基·多兰的下落
You can tell me where to find Mickey Dolan.
我不能透露多兰一案的相关信息
I can't discuss the Dolan case.
那可不行  我的手下失踪在外
That is not acceptable. My people are out there,
我都不知道他们是死是活
And I don't even know if they're dead or alive.
他现在在哪儿
Now where is he?
我们不知道他现在在哪儿
We have no idea where he is.
那人刚杀害了你的线人
That man just killed your informant.
你知道的  对吧
You realize that, don't you?
麦克默瑞神父不是我们的线人
Father McMurtry was not our informant.
多兰才是你们的线人吗
Dolan is your informant?
现在还不是  但我们知道他和麦克默瑞是朋友
Not yet, but we knew he and McMurtry were friends.
麦克默瑞正努力说服多兰
McMurtry was trying to get Dolan
做污点证人  告发奥莱利家族
to turn state's evidence against the O'Reilly family
以换得豁免权
in exchange for immunity.
我们只是让多兰过来商讨具体条款
We just brought Dolan in to discuss terms.
所以你将他加入了保护性监禁计划
So you have him in protective custody.
本来是的
He was.
今天他发现麦克默瑞神父被人枪击
Then today when he found out father McMurtry had been shot,
他就失去理智了
He lost it.
多兰躲过两名守卫的监视
Dolan slipped out on the two agents who were guarding him
从安全藏身处逃脱
And he escaped the safe house.
等等
Wait a minute.
如果案发当晚  他被联邦警察监禁  那么
If he was in federal custody on the night of the murder, then--
那麦克默瑞神父就不是他杀的
Then he didn't kill father Mcmurtry.
那是谁杀的  谁有杀人动机
So who did? Who had motive?
奥莱利家族
The O'reillys.
多兰的证词会将他们全部送入监狱
It was Dolan's testimony that would send them all up the river.
所以他们都逃离本市
That's why they're all leaving town.
所以他们才杀了麦克默瑞  就为了引他出来
That's why they killed Mcmurtry--to draw him out.
多兰在追杀谋害神父的人
So Dolan is hunting whoever killed the priest,
而奥莱利家族正追杀多兰
And the O'reillys are hunting Dolan.
双方都会杀掉一切挡路的人
And both sides will take out anyone who gets in their way.
枪  快捡枪
The gun! Get the gun!
你在做什么  里奥
What are you doing, Leo?
我的任务
My job.
你是谁
Who are you?
这么说吧  我是个独立杀手
Let's just say, I'm an independent contractor
只是想接近目标人物
trying to get close to his mark.
这么说你不是目击证人
So you're not a witness?
你只是假装的
You're just pretending.
是你杀了麦克默瑞
You killed McMurtry
因为你的目标是多兰
Because you're trying to get to Dolan,
你知道如果你假装是目击证人
And you knew that if you played the witness,
他就会主动来找你
He would come to you.
脑子转得挺快嘛
Quick study.
何必弄这么复杂呢
Why the charades?
为什么你不直接杀了卡塞尔和我
Why didn't you just kill Castle and me?
那样的话  想假扮目击证人就有点不太像了
Well, it's a little hard to play the innocent witness
毕竟身边躺着两具尸体嘛
with two bodies lying around,
所以我只能配合你们假装一起逃跑
So I had to go along with the whole "on the run" thing.
现在快没时间了  我得展开下一步行动了
But now time has run out, and I have to make my next move.
你  你的电话呢
You, where's your phone?
听着  你不会想这样的
Look, you--you don't want to do this.
杀害一个警察
Killing a cop?
你知道那会带来怎样的麻烦
You know what kind of trouble that brings.
杀了她
Kill her?
相信我  我没打算杀了她
Trust me, I'm not planning to kill her.
麦克默瑞就很相信你  瞧瞧他的下场
Well, Mcmurtry trusted you, and look what happened to him.
你认为是我杀了乔伊吗
You think I killed Joey?
乔伊曾是我最好的朋友
Joey was my best friend,
尽管后来我们的命运朝着完全不同的方向前进
long after our lives went off in separate directions.
他从未放弃过我
He never gave up on me.
我永远不会伤害他
I'd never hurt him.
但我可不会对那个杀害他的人手下留情
I can't say the same for whoever iced him.
所以我得和那个目击证人谈谈
That's why I need to talk to the witness
不然你们就将他列入保护性监禁计划中了
before you put him in protective custody--
那样我就可以查出是
So I could find out who the hell
哪个狗娘养的杀害了乔伊
the son of a bitch was that took Joey out.
我怎么知道我可以信任你
How do I know I can trust you?
你不知道
You don't.
但你也没必要知道
But you don't have to.
你只要坐在这儿  等着我的电话响就行了
All you have to do is sit here and wait for my phone to ring.
等我得到我想要的
And then when I get what I want,
我们都可以离开
we all walk away,
活着离开
alive.
不管你信不信我都没关系
whether you believe me or not.
来  拿着电话
Here. Take the phone.
-你抓住他们了吗  -抱歉  迈基
- You get 'em? - Sorry, Mickey.
或许你该派更多的人过来
Maybe you shoulda sent more guys.
或许吧
Maybe.
我低估你了  探长
I underestimated you, detective.
是啊  如果是我  就不会再犯这种错了
Yeah, well, I wouldn't make that same mistake again,
尤其是如果你伤害了卡塞尔的话
especially if you hurt Castle.
我们来做笔交易怎么样
So how about if we make a trade?
我把你的作家还给你  你把目击证人带来给我
I'll give you your writer back, you bring me the witness.
不  不行
No, no.
除非先让我知道卡塞尔平安  否则我不答应任何事
I'm not agreeing to anything until I know that Castle is okay.
大作家  你来接
Shakespeare, you're up.
凯特
Kate.
卡塞尔
Castle.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
嗯  我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
听着  尽管这听起来有点疯狂
Listen, crazy as this sounds,
但我觉得迈基只是想谈谈而已
I actually think mickey just wants to talk.
一切都会没事的
Everything's gonna be fine.
但愿如此吧
I hope so.
或许我们可以替二老重新安排一些活动
Maybe then we can reschedule something with our parents.
或许我们可以一起去看棒球赛
Maybe we could go and watch a baseball game.
就是  那种...
You know, something that
咱们四个都会喜欢的活动
all four of us can enjoy.
考虑好没
Good enough?
咱们在哪见
Where should we meet?
科斯特勒大桥下
Under the Costello Bridge--
离你们三个街区远  走过去十五分钟能到
It's about 3 blocks from you, in about 15 minutes.
演技不错
Well played.
走吧
Let's go.
我说的话并非都是假的
Not everything I told you was a lie.
我确实看过心理医生
I really did have a shrink.
不过根据他的诊断
But then he diagnosed me
我是一个具有杀人倾向的反社会人士  所以
as a sociopath with homicidal tendencies, so...
我只好杀了他
had to kill him.
听着  里奥  这不是你想做的事情
Listen, Leo, you don't want to do this.
杀掉一个警察会让你惹上
Okay, killing a cop's gonna bring you a lot of grief
纽约警方  还有联调局
from the NYPD, the FBI.
放我走吧
Just let me go.
不好意思  恕难从命
Yeah. Sorry. Can't do that.
不过你那段恋情确实不错
I did find your relationship fascinating, though.
你跟卡塞尔的感情还真是问题多多
Boy, you and Castle have some real issues.
你们没能解决问题真是可惜了
It's a shame you won't be able to work 'em out.
不过正如我说的
But like I said,
人生苦短
life's too short.
他们在那
There they are.
不
No!
这是怎么...
What the...
看来你打偏了
Looks like you missed.
把枪放下
Drop the act.
咱们都清楚  你的枪里已经没子弹了
We both know you emptied your clip into that car.
你是怎么识破的
How'd you get on to me?
我倒希望这是自己的功劳
I wish I could say I figured it out,
可惜是这边这位莎翁发现的
but Shakespeare over here made the call.
你说我妈妈也会喜欢看棒球赛时我就觉得不对
Once you made that comment about my mom enjoying baseball--
要开这种玩笑得等六个月后再说
I knew we were about six months away from joking about that.
事情肯定不妙
Something had to be up.
我只想问你一个问题
All I wanted to do is ask you a question
是谁杀了我的朋友
about who killed my friend.
迈基
Mickey.
看来已经有答案了
Well, I guess I don't have to ask that anymore.
迈基  别
Mickey, don't.
他无情地杀害了乔伊
He killed Joey in cold blood.
我知道  可乔伊不希望看到你这样
Yeah, I know, but what would Joey want?
你说过他从来没有放弃你
You said he never gave up on you.
如果你扣动扳机
If you pull that trigger,
你就辜负了他
you're giving up on him.
就算我死了这事也没完
This doesn't end with me.
奥莱利那帮人  他们会再派人过来的
The O'reillys, they'll just send somebody else.
你死定了
You're a dead man.
知道不
You know what?
我无所谓
I can live with that.
把他的枪拿走
Take his gun.
把双手举起来
Put your hands up.
好吧  好吧  好吧
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah.
-我还以为你死了  -不
- I thought I lost you. - No.
不  不会的  不会的
No, never, never.
来  我把这玩意儿...
Here. Let me get you out of...
弄下来
Get this off.
给你的
And these are for you.
咱们走吧
Now let's get the hell out of here.
好主意
That sounds good to me.
不好意思  不好意思
Excuse me. Excuse me.
能把我们捎回去吗
Can you help us get a ride?
我们得在这待好一会儿
We're gonna be tied up here for a bit.
你们打个车怎么样
Why don't you guys just take a cab?
有没有搞错
Really?
-走吧  -嗯
- Uh... let's... - Yeah.
能借我20块钱不
Can you spot me 20 bucks?
多兰又回到联邦看管之下了
Dolan's back in federal custody.
他打算提供对同犯不利的证据了吗
So is he gonna turn state's?
不知道  不过他愿意
Oh, I don't know, but he is offering
就过去的犯罪行为坐几年牢
to serve some time for his past crimes.
看来麦克默瑞神父还是感化到他了
Sounds like Father Mcmurtry got to him after all.
里奥呢
And what about Leo?
他绑架了一个警察  还当面对其
He confessed to killing Mcmurtry
承认了谋杀麦克默瑞的罪行
in front of a cop that he had taken hostage.
肯定得把大牢坐穿了才行
He's going away for a long time.
直到现在
After all this time,
我还是不敢相信他是个坏人
I still can't believe that he was the bad guy.
贝克特警探  卡塞尔先生
Detective Beckett, Mr. Castle,
见到你们俩回来真好
so nice to have you two back.
回来真好
Nice to be back.
虽然我们都很担心你们
Well, as worried as we were,
不过担心程度估计还是比不上你们那几位
I don't think we were nearly as concerned as your folks.
我们那几位
Our folks?
嗯  我们在找你们时
Yeah. I called them
给他们打了电话
when we were trying to find you guys.
你妈妈
Your mom is, uh--
别...说了
I... say no more.
他们在休息室
You can pick 'em up at the break room.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们也不能总是回避这个问题
Well, I guess we can't avoid dealing with them forever.
没错  不过
No, but you know what?
谁在乎他们之间相处不来
Who cares if they don't get along?
他们又不是我们
They aren't us.
就算我们在理论上不搭又怎样
And... so what if we don't make sense on paper?
我们又不活在理论里
We don't live our lives on paper.
如果真是这样  我们也不会吃惊或者...
And if we did, we'd never be astounded or...
惊讶
surprised.
这是怎么回事
Aw. How did that even happen?
不知道  事已至此  就这样吧
I don't know, but let-- let--let's just go with it.
爸
Dad.